<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dhanangw writings</title><link>http://dhanangw.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on dhanangw writings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://dhanangw.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>John C. Bogle - The Little Book of Common Sense Investing</title><link>http://dhanangw.github.io/posts/little-book-of-common-investing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dhanangw.github.io/posts/little-book-of-common-investing/</guid><description>This book feels like a condensed argument by John C. Bogle endorsing Index Fund investing. The main idea is simple and easy to understand, supported by many arguments in each chapters. Get the book here.
About The Author John C. &amp;ldquo;Jack&amp;rdquo; Bogle was the man who popularised Index Fund investing. Applauded by Warren Buffet &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;has probably done more for the American investor than any man in the country.&amp;rdquo;
Takeaways It is better to buy stocks that are listed in an index fund and hold it for a long time.</description></item><item><title>Cara Deploy Python 3 di AWS Lambda</title><link>http://dhanangw.github.io/posts/aws-lambda-id/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dhanangw.github.io/posts/aws-lambda-id/</guid><description>Copied from Medium with slight correction
September 2018 lalu, saya mendapat kesempatan magang di kumparan sebagai Data Engineer. Sebagai tugas magang, saya ditugaskan membuat distributed web scraper untuk mengumpulkan data perhitungan Pemilu 2014 serta gambar scan C1 tiap TPS dari situs kawalpemilu.org.
Kami memutuskan untuk menggunakan Amazon Web Services (AWS). Worker dari distributed web scraper nya dijalankan di AWS Lambda karena Lambda memungkinkan kami tidak repot di maintenance, dan dapat mendukung concurrency secara otomatis.</description></item><item><title>Setup WireGuard VPN in Google Cloud Platform</title><link>http://dhanangw.github.io/posts/setup-wireguard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dhanangw.github.io/posts/setup-wireguard/</guid><description>Copied from Medium with slight correction
WireGuard VPN running on Google Compute Engine (GCE) Virtual Machine (VM) with Ubuntu 20.04 LTS. We’re going to put our WireGuard server in one of these Google Cloud Platform (GCP) regions because it’s free:
Oregon: us-west1 Iowa: us-central1 South Carolina: us-east1 GCE free tier specification is good enough for our VPN server.
Part 1: Set up GCP Networking Open a port through GCP’s firewall On GCP console, click the hamburger menu on the top-left corner, click &amp;ldquo;Networks&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;VPC Network&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Firewall&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Create Firewall&amp;rdquo; Create a name for our firewall rule in “Direction of traffic” choose “ingress” in “Targets” choose “All instances in the network” in “Source filter” choose “IP Ranges” in “IP Range” fill “0.</description></item></channel></rss>